Hello and welcome to Real easyy English We're back with another conversation in easyy English to help you learn I'm Georgie and I'm Neil don't forget that there's a video version
Of this podcast on our website BBC Learning English.com. you can read along with the subtitles and download a free worksheet.
Hello Neil how are you doing hi Georgie yeah I'm fine how are you Yes I'm very well too thank you today Neil in this conversation we're talking about moving house
So when was the last time you moved house Oh I moved house probably12 years ago Oh wow and why did you move to where you live now
Because my family was getting bigger more children need more space so we moved to somewhere bigger and further?
Out of London how about you I I rent my flat and the place I was living before,
The owners of the place wanted to sell the house.
So I needed to move because I couldn't live there anymore and also my friend had this flat and he was offering me very cheap rent so that's
Why I live there but i'm very happy there because it's, Between two really nice parks, it has good transport links and yeah,
It was a good a good decision and how was the move itself The move was actually.
Ve easy because I don't have many possessions I'm a bit of a minimalist the reason is because I moved country so I just didn't
Really have many things to bring back to the UK.
So I didn't need a big van or anything, I just ordered a taxi and put all of my bags in the taxi and it was very easy and what about you it was the opposite
Of that Oh no.
We had a removal van and some removal men who came and packed everything up in boxes to make sure that things.
Were easy to carry into the van and also that they didn't get damaged and then they drove all of our stuff to my new
House Yeah did you have.
Did you have any fragile bit so fragile means that it's easy to break not very strong plates and things did you have Yes, those things had to be wrapped and protected.
Otherwise they would break yes and did you have to move furniture as well Yeahep, we had to move sofas and cupboards and wardrobes
And heavy things like that yeah.
Does sound different to my experience, doesn't it, I didn't have any furniture to take do you find moving house exciting, scary, How do you feel about moving house?
I think it's both, it's exciting and scary, it's exciting because this is going to be your new life or where your new life will happen.
But it's also scary because you don't know what that's going to be like, you don't know what your neighbors are going to be like that's very true you don't know.
What your new friends are going to be like.
Yes, so there's lots of things that you don't know.
And that's scary, but also exciting.
Yeah, a lot of uncertainty for sure.
Yeah, I think it can depend.
It depends if you're moving somewhere better or worse, but yeah, I was quite excited when I moved because I knew that my new flat had a nice outdoorterrace.
As I said, we were close to parks and stuff so I was excited so Georgie, if you are planning a move, what do you need to do to prepare?
Well, you need to do things like setting up wfi in the new house, other bills like electricity and heating gas.
You need to put your name on the accounts, you need to plan what you're going to take,
So when you move it's a really good time to look at all of your possessions and think, What do I need maybe I can get rid of stuff so throw stuff away
Have you got any other ideas, what else can you do to prepare for remove you can hire a removal.
Company or van, if you're doing it yourself, if you're, if you need to transport your stuff to your new house, you can't just use a taxi, yeah, sounds like a lot of work.
I don't want to move anytime soon No, you me neither, no.
Okay, let's recap the language we heard during the conversation we heard possessions which are the things that you own or have, for example, my phone and my clothes are my possessions.
We talked about removal vans, a removal van is a large vehicle that people put your possessions into to go from one home to another.
And the company is called a Res company or removals firm We heard packing and packing is where you put your own things into boxes so that a removal
Firm can take them to your new home.
And we heard fragile, Fr is an adjective which describes something that can break easily, for example, glass.
Glass is fragile That's it for this episode of real easy English don't forget to test what you've learned using the free worksheet on our website go tobbclearningenglish.com. .
We'll be back next week with another conversation in Ey English bye for now, goodbye.